From Sena?
星奈から
えっと
Okay...
小鳩ちゃん生誕祭のこと
"About the Kobato-mas party!
We're going to Nagaya together
on Sunday to buy her presents!"
小鳩ちゃんの誕生日プレゼントを買いに日曜一緒に永夜に行くわよ
日曜か
Sunday, huh? Well,
I don't have anything planned...
まあ　予定もないしな
"OK. We'll meet Sunday at 100
in the waiting area at Toya Station."
オーケー　日曜午後一時　遠夜駅ホーム待合室でっと
Shiguma Rika
Aaah!
"Aaah!
ああん
Rika feels Eros coming from the
quietly towering telephone poles!
静かに高くそびえる電柱にエロスを感じます
She wants to be tied up!
She wants to do the deed!
取り合えず縛られたいです
まぐわりたいです
しかしよく考えると後ろから攻められるのもいいかもしれません
But when she thinks about it,
being taken from behind could work too!"
"Shut. Up."
"Read it vertically!"
経て読むですよ
Vertically?
経て読み
"Let's... go on... a date... tomorrow."
あしたデートしましょう
"No."
いやです
お願いします
"Please! I want you to help me
pick out a present for Kobato-san."
小鳩さんのプレゼント選ぶに付き合って欲しいのです
なら素直にそう書けよ
Then just write that.
"For the esteemed Mr. Hasegawa Kodaka.
一筆啓上　羽瀬川小鷹様へ
Dear Mr. Hasegawa Kodaka,
拝啓　羽瀬川小鷹様
I hope you are well during
this pleasant fall season.
爽秋の候　貴兄におかれましては 益々ご健勝のこと　誠にお喜び申し上げます
Please forgive me for
the suddenness of this letter.
突然のお手紙を差し上げるご無礼をお許しくださいませ
I'm terribly sorry to trouble
you when you are surely very busy,
ご多忙の中大変恐縮ですが
この度は貴兄にどうしてもお願いしたき儀が御座いまして
but I take pen in hand now because
there is something I feel I must ask you.
こうして筆を執った次第です
I shall make so bold as
to come straight to the point.
それでは　不躾ながら早速本題へと移らせていただきます
What should I give to your honored sister?
妹君への贈り物は何が良いですか
With my best wishes for your health and..."
末筆ながら　兄貴のご健康と…
って前置きなげえよ
That opening was too long!
"Don't worry if you're busy or whatever.
用事があるなら別にいいけど
お前の妹の誕生日プレゼント選びを手伝ってもらいたい
- I want you to help me pick
out a present for your sister.
- You, too?
お前もか
Tomorrow would be best
since there's not much time,
誕生会まで時間がないので出来れば明日がいいのだが
別にどうしてもお前が必要というわけではなく
- but whatever, I don't need you to be there,
- And it's gratuitously long...
何か無駄に長文だし
別に用事があるなら別にいい
so don't worry if you're busy or whatever.
別にプレゼント選びくらい一人でも
- It's not like I can't pick out one
little present on my own or whatever."
- More like, why all the "whatever"s?
つうか「別に」が多いな
別に問題はないからな
Eh, fine.
まあいいか
Yo.
おす
- The train bound for Nagaya
is approaching platform three.
- Looks like everybody's here.
全員揃ってんな
よし　そんじゃ行くか
- Please stay behind the line for your safety.
- Okay, let's go, I guess.
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
Yeah, you played dumb
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
I'll walk another step toward your side
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
その手にだって届きそうさ
I bet I can even reach your hand
"Haganai NEXT"
想像しちゃダメ
It's more than I imagined... every
day's a roller coaster
ジェットコースターな毎日
引き締めて前を向いて
I always barreled ahead with everything I had
いつも駆け抜けたら
ずっと続きはしないね
Our time won't last forever, now will it?
僕らの時間は今しかないから
Now is all we have, so let's make
sure we remember this moment
この瞬間刻みづけよう
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
知らないフリしたって
Yeah, you played dumb
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
I'll walk another step toward your side
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
受け止めるように
So I can take your hand
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Yeah, I'm always gazing at the sky
見上げてばかりだって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I'm still drawn to it
憧れてる今も
One more time! I'll reach out
to you as many times as you need
もう一回
何度でも手を伸ばそう
あの星だって届きそうさ
I bet I can even reach that star
"He's My Brother, But As Long As
There's Love, It Doesn't Matter
If He Gets More
Sisters, Right?"
You sit too, Yozora. Over here.
夜空も座れよ　こっち
I don't care about sitting!
What are Meat and the others doing here?!
そんなことはどうでもいい
なぜ肉達がここにいるのだ
Oh, sorry, I guess I forgot to tell you.
悪い　伝えるのを忘れてたな
We're all buying Kobato a present,
so bringing people isn't a problem, right?
皆小鳩の誕生日プレゼント買いに行くんだし
人数増えてもいいだろう
Sure, but this doesn't sit right with me.
増えてもいいけど釈然としないわね
Especially the part where you
really don't seem to think anything of it.
特にあんたが本当になんとも思ってなさそうなとこが
What did I do?
俺がなんだって
Forget it, idiot!
なんでもないわよ　馬鹿
Rika had a feeling this might happen...
どうせこんなことじゃないかと思ってましたよ
We must know when we're beaten, everyone.
諦めが肝心なんです　皆さん
得心致しました　理科殿
I quite agree, Rika-dono.
Rika wonders: is this obliviousness real?
この鈍さを本当に素なんですかね
Or has he deliberately embraced obliviousness?
それとも　あえて望んでそうなったんでしょうか
Rika?
理科
Oh, it's nothing! Rika simply thought,
"He's as fascinating as ever."
なんでもないですよ
相変わらず面白いなと思っただけです
Excuse me?
何だ　そりゃ
And are you wearing the
uniform and lab coat again?
つうか　今日も制服に白衣かよ
Is there something strange about that?
何か変ですか
You're obsessed with your hair lately,
but you don't care about your clothes.
最近のお前　髪は凝ってるのに服には無頓着だから
It's majorly weird.
違和感半端ないんだよ
I mean, today you randomly got
highlights to make your hair look fuller.
今日も何気にメッシュ入れてふわっと立体的に見えるようにしてるし
R-Rika didn't expect you to
notice so much. Not bad, Sempai.
そ　そこに気付くとは
やりますね　先輩
でも理科は服に拘っても意味ない気がするんですよね
But Rika feels like there isn't much
point in worrying about her clothes.
It's not like her efforts would help, since
you ignore her even when she's stripping...
生着替えすらスルーされる程度の理科が頑張ったところで
But Rika's cute on the outside,
理科も見た目は可愛いし
so I think cute clothes would
look as good on her as anyone else...
可愛い服も普通に似合うと思うんだけどな
Huh? Wait, did I say that out loud again?
あれ　もしかして俺また声に出してたのか
Yes, loud and clear!
それはもう思いっきり
By the way, Sena-sempai.
時に星奈先輩
What?
何よ
Rika thought she'd look at
some clothes, since we're shopping.
せっかくなので　服を見てみようと思うのですが
Do you have any stores you recommend?
お勧めのお店とかないですか
Y-You want my recommendations?
あ　あたしのお勧め
Yes! You're stylish, so Rika
would like to learn from you.
はい　星奈先輩おしゃれなので参考にさせていただければと
Um... I-I don't go to Nagaya that often,
えっと　あ　あたし　あんまり永夜には行かないから
and I usually use posh name-brand
shops near my house, so I can't really...
普段はうちの近くの高級ブランドショップとかだし
There's nothing near your
house but mountains and rice fields.
お前うちの周りって山とか田圃ばっかじゃねえ
Sena-sempai...
星奈先輩
Sena-anego...
星奈の姉御
I'm sorry. I lied. I have
Stella buy all my clothes,
御免　あたし嘘ついてた
服はいつもステラにお任せで
and she does my hair and makeup, too.
髪もメイクもやってもらってる
何よ　あんた　何かむかつくわね
What was that for?! You're pissing me off!
A femininity power of just 5, huh? What trash.
女子力たったの5か　ゴミめ
A Scouter?
スカウターか
While we're at it, where do
you buy yours, Yozora-sempai?
ちなみに夜空先輩はどちらで
On the internet. I find a model in
a fashion magazine or the store site
ネット通販だ
雑誌とか通販サイトのモデルが着ていた物を一式まとめて買っている
and just buy her whole outfit.
Rika is jealous that you look good
dressed straight out of a fashion mag!
ファッション誌そのままの格好でも似合っちゃうあたりが羨ましいです
You're ultra-cute today, too.
今日もばっちり可愛いですし
"Cute," you say?!
可愛い…だと
Yep! Very feminine, very sexy-cute.
はい　女の子らしくてとてもエロ可愛いです
女の子　エロ　かわ…
"Feminine"?
"Sexy... cute"?
Y-Yeah.
That can't be! This was in the
"How to Rock the Boyish Look" section!
馬鹿な　だって雑誌の「ボーイッシュ着こなしテク」コーナーに載ってたんだぞ
Yozora-sempai...
夜空先輩
Listen, Yozora, a "boyish" look
doesn't actually equal a mannish one.
夜空　あのな
ボーイッシュな格好ってのは
別に男っぽい格好とイコールってわけじゃないからな
It's just a technique to
draw out your girlish cuteness
あくまで女の子の可愛さを引き出すために
by mixing in some pieces
with an androgynous feel.
中性的な雰囲気を加味する手法ですね
More like, anyone paying attention
to the outside world would notice that!
つうか　普通に生活してれば気付くだろう
Not a lot of men walk around
exposing their thighs and belly buttons!
太ももやへそだして歩いてる男なんてそうそういないって
But... I've never cared
how any other man dresses...
だって　他の男の格好なんて気にしたことないし
Huh?
N-Nothing!
なんでもない
I'm going to do some other shopping.
Kodaka, you can't come with me!
私はちょっとほかの買い物に行ってくる
小鷹は付いてくるな
That's fine, but will you be okay in the crowds?
いいけど　大丈夫か　人ごみ
Rika will come with you.
理科もご一緒します
I see...
そうか
Yukimura, would you mind going
with Yozora and Rika in my place?
幸村　俺の代わりに夜空と理科に付き合ってくれないか
Look after them so they don't collapse
when they're surrounded by people.
人ごみで倒れたりしないように面倒を見てやってくれ
はい　お任せください　兄貴
Yes, Aniki. Leave it to me.
We'll be going, then.
それでは行って参ります
Okay, thanks.
頼むな
So, how about the two of
us just kind of look around?
さて　そんじゃ　二人で適当に見て回るか
Yeah!
Hey, Kodaka, what kind of present would
up my approval rating with Kobato-chan?
ねえ 小鷹　小鳩ちゃんに何をプレゼントしたら好感度上がるのかしら
Probably FMN goods, right?
やっぱ「クロネク」のグッズとか
Well, she's pretty much got
everything she wants already...
あいつ欲しいものは大体もう持ってるからな
Oh, and please don't get anything too expensive.
ちなみに　あんまり高級なものは勘弁してくれ
Huh. You're a surprisingly responsible guardian.
意外としっかり保護者やってるのね　あんた
What would be good, then?
じゃあ　何がいいのよ
What about something you'd like?
例えば自分がもらって嬉しいものとか
That would be Kobato-chan, of course!
それはもちろん小鳩ちゃん
You can't have her!
やらねえよ
Hey, I just found something
that Kobato-chan would 100% like.
あったぞ　小鳩が100パーセント喜ぶもの
What?
何
Meat.
肉
Not Meat as in you, meat as in food!
お前じゃなくて　食材の肉だ
I know that, sheesh.
わかってるわよ　それぐらい
She loves anything with meat in it,
so she's sure to like it if you give her meat.
小鳩は肉料理なら何でも好きだから
肉やれば絶対喜ぶ
But raw food is a questionable
choice for a birthday present.
でも誕生日プレゼントに生ものっていうのはどうなのよ
I can't believe Sena just
corrected my common sense...
星奈に常識をさとされるとは
Well, let's save that for a last
resort, and keep looking a little...
まあ　それ系は最後の手段ってことで
もう少しいろいろ見て
Wh-Whoa, wait a second!
ちょ　ちょっと待ってくれ
What is it?
何よ
Th-This is...
こ　これは
Honestly, why should I have to keep
you company shopping for a whole hour?
まったくなんであたしがあんたの買い物に一時間も付き合わされるのよ
Normally it's the opposite!
普通逆でしょう
I'm sorry.
すみません
And I don't see what's so
fun about looking at frying pans.
ったく　フライパンなんか見てて何が楽しいんだか
Whoa, there, D-fol pans aren't just any pans!
おっと　ディフォームのフライパンをそこらのと一緒にするなよ
And I'll tell you exactly why!
詳しく説明してやろう
Not necessary.
しなくていい
あんたって本当になんか　変わってるわね
You really are sort of weird, aren't you?
What's wrong with liking cookware?
いいじゃねえか　調理器具好きでも
It's not like that's your only issue, idiot.
別にそれだけってわけじゃないわよ　馬鹿
Anyway, Yozora and the
others are taking forever...
にしても　夜空達買い物長いな
Girls always take forever to shop.
女の子の買い物は長いのよ
That's what gal games say.
ギャルゲーで言ってた
You learned that from a game?
ゲームからの知識かよ
あんたさ　夜空とか理科とか幸村のことどう思ってるの
Say, what do you think of
Yozora and Rika and Yukimura?
What do you mean?
どうって
Jeez, you're just so... Oh, never mind.
もうなんかな
まあいいわ
So, don't you want a girlfriend or anything?
じゃあ　あんたさ　彼女とか欲しくないの
I guess I don't not want one...
欲しくなくはないってとこかな
That's not very definite.
はっきりしないわね
Well, for now my goal is friends.
俺の当面の目標は友達だからな
A boring guy with no friends
can't get a girlfriend anyway, right?
そもそも　一人も友達がいないようなつまんないやつに
彼女なんかできないだろう
I don't think that's true.
そんなこともないと思うけど
Hmm?
Jeez, you're just so...
もう　何だかな
Oh, never mind!
まあ　いいわ
Why do you keep saying that?
さっきからなんだよ　お前
Oh, right, Sena...
そうだ　星奈
Um... Wh-What do you think about the
fact that Yozora and I used to be friends?
そのう　夜空と俺が昔友達だったってこと
お前はどう思ってるんだ
Hmm...
I guess I panicked a
little when I first found out,
そりゃ聞いた時にはちょっとなんか焦っちゃったけどさ
but when I thought it over,
I figured it doesn't matter much.
よく考えたら　別にどうでもいいかなって
D-Doesn't matter?
どうでもいい
I mean, it's in the past, right?
What's important is the present.
だって過去のことでしょう
大事なのは今なのよ
Maybe so.
そうかもな
Well, not that I know
what Yozora's intentions are.
まあ　夜空がどういうつもりなのか知らないけどね
About what?
何が
Nothing.
別に　ただ負ける気がしないってだけ
I'm just saying I don't
think I'll lose, that's all.
それだけよ
Also, Kodaka... and this is important,
so make sure you remember it.
それとねえ　小鷹
これ大事なことだから　よく覚えておきなさい
Anybody I like obviously can't be boring!
このあたしが気に入ってる人間がつまんないやつなわけないじゃない
ど　どうですかね　小鷹先輩
Wh-What do you think, Kodaka-sempai?
店員さんに勧められるままに買っちゃったんですけど
I bought exactly what the clerk recommended.
Um, well, it's... It's like,
"Huh, Rika pulls it off when she tries."
なんつうか　そのう
お前もやればできるんだなって感じ
Rika will choose to take that as a compliment.
一応褒め言葉として受け取っておきます
兄貴　わたくしはどうでしょう
What do you think of me?
I received these from Yozora-anego.
夜空の姉御から受け継ぎました
Whoa, Yukimura, not bad!
幸村　お前やるじゃ
E-Er, they look nice on you.
えっと　似合ってるぞ
Thank you, Aniki.
ありがとう御座います　兄貴
And then there's...
でもって
あのね
Look, you...
You're... you're just so... I can't believe you!
もうあんた　ちょっと　本当　あんたね
Shut up, Meat. I don't feel good, so keep quiet.
うるさいぞ　肉
気分が悪いから　騒ぐな
A track suit...
ジャージ
I found it at a sports store.
What's wrong with it?
スポーツ用品売り場で見つけた　いいだろう
Anyway, this neighborhood isn't for me.
にしてもこの街は私に向いていない
- I'll grab a present from a store near my place.
- Huh?!
プレゼントは地元の店で適当に探す
Rika's sorry, but she wants to go home now too.
すいません　理科ももう帰りたいです
Excuse me?!
すまん　星奈
Sorry, Sena, but my bags are heavy
and I don't want to walk around with them.
俺も荷物重くて歩き回りたくない
H-Hey!
ちょっと
御伴します　兄貴
I shall accompany you, Aniki.
Jeez, you're all so...
Why are you all such sad cases?!
ったく　あんたら　もう　何でそんなに残念なのよ
King
Horse
Yep, perfect! I'm amazing.
ばっちり　さすがあたし
But this whole thing is a little lame
for Kobato-chan's birthday party.
それにしても
せっかく小鳩ちゃんの誕生会なのに なんか地味ね
Well, we don't actually know what
a normal birthday party looks like.
俺達に普通の誕生会なんてものわからんからな
I figure it's about right.
こんなもんだろう
Incidentally, Aniki, what
should one do at a birthday party?
ところで　兄貴
誕生パーティっと言うものは何をすればいいのですか
Hmm, hand over presents and eat
cake, right? But then what do you do?
プレゼント渡して　ケーキ食べるだろう
後は何をすればいいんだ
皆でゲームとかするんじゃないでしょうか
Perhaps everyone plays a game after that.
We don't have any besides Meat's
gal games and Rika's computer games.
ゲームなど肉のギャルゲーと理科のパソコンゲームくらいしかないが
Kobato
Kukuku...
I don't want to go
- Doing that as a group doesn't sound fun...
- Oh, please. Sheesh, is she nervous?
そんなものみんなでやってどうするな
おいおい　ったく　緊張してんのか　あいつ
Please come.
There's a big cake.
- Rika supposes we should
have prepared a party game.
- Oh, please. Sheesh, is she nervous?
パーティゲームでも用意しておけばよかったですね
She doesn't have any analog games in her lab...
理科室にもアナログゲームはありませんし
Then we'll go to the nearest toy
store and buy one. Like Twister!
それじゃ　近くのおもちゃ屋で買ってくるわよ　ツイスターとか
Why Twister?
なぜツイスター
If you're already at the door,
you should just get in here!
そこまで来てんなら　さっさと入ってくりゃいいのに
Happy birthday, Kobato-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう　小鳩ちゃん
I thought I should try popping mine.
とりあえず鳴らしてみました
Okay, then!
じゃあ
何だこれ
What is this?
Now, Kobato-chan, you sit here!
さあさあ　小鳩ちゃん　こっち座って
ケーキ　ケーキ
It's cake time! And... ta-da!
せいの
Well? Do you like it, Kobato-chan?!
どうどう　気に入ってくれた　小鳩ちゃん
You always have to go a step too far, don't you?
貴様は
本当にいちいち余計なことをするな
What's your problem?!
That cake is too lovely for words!
何よ　最高にラブリーなケーキじゃない
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Happy birthday to you
♪ Happy birthday dear ♪
Happy birthday dear
- ♪ Kobato ♪
- ♪ Kodaka's little sister ♪
- ♪ Kobato-chan ♪
- ♪ Kobato-san ♪
- ♪ honored sister ♪
小鳩さん
小鳩ちゃん
小鷹の妹
Come on, guys, get that in synch.
いや　ここは合わせろよ
♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
Happy birthday to you
Go on, Kobato, blow out the candles.
ほら　小鳩　蝋燭
Uh-huh.
おめでとう　小鳩ちゃん
- Congratulations, Kobato-chan!
- Good job!
よかったな
Hey, what was that for?!
ちょっと何すんのよ
Whoops, my hand slipped.
おっと　手が滑った
Here, Sempai, say "ah"!
ほら　先輩　あーん
いい香りがするんですよ
These things smell nice.
It's a talisman.
お札です
Jeez, so you got meat after all?
何だよ　結局肉か
Shut up, you! I thought you
might want to eat some too...
うるさいわね　あんたも食べたいかと思って
Meat, that's just too masochistic.
肉　自虐的過ぎるだろう
Isn't that great, Kobato?
We're having sukiyaki tonight!
よかったな　小鳩　今夜はすき焼だぞ
Enjoy it as if it were me, okay?
あたしだと思って美味しく食べてね
No!
いや
Sukiyaki!
すき焼
Well, somebody's in a good mood.
ご機嫌だな　お前
Today is a good day!
今日はいい日じゃあ
Okay, I'm going to buy ingredients,
so you go home ahead of me.
んじゃ　すき焼の材料を買って帰るから
お前は先に帰ってろ
Come home quickly, my kin.
早く帰るのだぞ　我が眷属よ
おい
Hey!
っげ　お兄ちゃん　なぜここに
Geh, Big Brother! What are you doing here?!
Excuse me? That's my house.
What are you doing?
俺んちの前で何言ってる
お前こそ何やってんだ
I was only trying to sneak a peek
inside. Is that a no-no, Big Brother?
こっそり中を伺おうとしていただけなんだげど
駄目　お兄ちゃん
It's a no-no. And why do
you want to see inside, anyway?
駄目　つうかなんで中なんか
Big Brother is home!
お兄ちゃん　帰ってきた
Hi, Maria, I didn't know you were here.
マリア　来てたのか
Did you get Kate to bring you?
ケイトに送ってもらったのか
Yep. This is the one
thing that hag is good for...
うん　あの婆はこういう時だけは役に立つな…
Hey, what are you still doing here, hag?!
なんでまだおるんじゃ　婆
You brat, before I brought
you here, didn't you say
お前　お兄ちゃんうちに連れて行く前
"I'll be grateful forever, Big Sister!"?!
「お姉様に一生感謝します」って言ったよな
So what was that just now?!
なのに今なんつうった
Um, er... Shut up, crappy old hag!
あのう　そのう
うるさい　くそ婆
本当しょうがないガキだな
Honestly, what a problem child.
Says the girl who was
worried enough to spy on her.
その妹が心配でのぞいてたくせに
Well, how about you join us
for sukiyaki, since you're here?
まあ　せっかくだからお前もすき焼食ってっけ
Sukiyaki?! Can I really?!
すき焼　いいの
Y-Yeah...
My beautiful day has turned poopy.
せっかくいい日が　うんこ色になった
So you're Kobato-chan,
Big Brother's real-life sister, eh?
君がお兄ちゃんのリアル妹の小鳩ちゃんか
"Big Brother"?
お兄ちゃん
That's what my sister Maria calls him.
うちのマリアがお兄ちゃんのこと　そう呼んでるからね
If he's Maria's big brother,
マリアのお兄ちゃんなら
and I'm her sister, and I'm younger
than he is, then he's my big brother too.
マリアと姉妹で
お兄ちゃんより年下の私にとってもお兄ちゃんというわけだ
Gah!
なんだ
What's wrong?
Bro! Why?! Why do you keep getting
more little sisters, you big dummy?!
あんちゃん
あんちゃんはもう
あんちゃんは何ですぐに妹ばっかり作るんじゃ馬鹿ったれ
Hey, calm down! I didn't adopt them;
they just decided to call me that.
落ち着けって
あいつらが勝手に呼んでるだけだから
Say, why did Maria come over all of a sudden?
ところでマリアはなんで突然うちに来たんだ
She said she had to talk to Kobato-chan.
小鳩ちゃんに用事だってさ
What business does that foolish minion of God
愚かなる神の手先は偉大なる夜の王である我に如何なる用だ
have with me, the great ruler of the night?
What just happened to Kobato-chan?
小鳩ちゃん　どうしちゃったの
Do me a favor and just let it go.
気にしないでやってくれ
O-Okay...
ほら　マリア
Hey, Maria, hurry up and
give Kobato-chan your present!
早く　小鳩ちゃんにプレゼント渡せ
- Present?
プレゼント
Gah! Why did you tell her,
you poopy crappy hag?!
何で言うんじゃ　うんこくそ婆
What's the big deal?
いいじゃ　別に
I'm generously giving you
a present, so be grateful.
プレゼントくれてやるのだ　有り難く思うがいい
B-Birthdays are important,
お誕生日だけは大事なので
so I'll give it to you even
though you're a poopy vampire.
うんこ吸血鬼だけどくれてやるのだ
You're an evil being, after all!
お前は邪悪な存在だからな
You should let its divine power help you
mend your ways and become a good girl!
それを付けて聖なる力で改心していい子になるといいぞ
ククク　愚かなる聖女め
Foolish holy woman.
Divine powers don't work on me!
我に聖なる力など通じぬ
How dare you! Repent, you evil poopy vampire!
なんだと
悔い改めるのだ　うんこ吸血鬼め
Whatever you say, it still won't work!
何を言われようと通じぬ
Ow, that hurt!
痛いだろうが
Dummy!
Come on, sukiyaki time.
ほら　すき焼食うぞ
"Sukiyaki"? I know what that is!
It's that tasty-sounding thing!
すき焼
私すき焼って知ってるぞ　あの美味しそうなやつだな
Yay! I'll help set the table!
お皿出すの手伝うぞ
小鳩　プレゼントのお礼　言っとけ
Say thank you for the present, Kobato.
Tha... Th-Thank... you.
あ　ありが…とう
Huh? Did you say something?
何か言ったか
N-Never mind, you dummy!
なんでもないわ　アホ
What, you poopy vampire?!
なんだと　このうんこ吸血鬼
Dummy! Jerk!
アホタレ　馬鹿
Poopy vampire!
うんこ吸血鬼
You worked hard, Big Brother.
お兄ちゃん　お疲れ
I only got two pieces of meat!
And there were two whole kilos...
俺　二切れしか肉食ってねえ
二キロもあったのに
Those girls really ate a lot, huh?
よく食べたね　あの子達
So did you.
お前もな
I'm so stuffed, I feel sleepy.
満腹になったら眠くなってきた
Big Brother, can we stay the night?
お兄ちゃん　今日は泊まっててもいい
Fine with me.
別にいいぞ
Really?!
本当に
Thank...
ありが…
お前本当に15才か
Are you really fifteen?
I turned sixteen a
while back. And check this out.
この間16になったよ
ちなみに
これ
その時にマリアがくれたんだ
Maria gave it to me for my birthday.
Huh, a locket?
ロケットか
What is this?
何だこれ
Maria gave me the cicada shell, and
I got someone I know to make this for me.
マリアがくれた蝉の抜け殻を
知り合いに頼んで加工してもらったんだ
But Kobato-chan's matches hers...
あっちはお揃いなのにな
You've got a tough time, huh?
お前も大変だな
I'm a big sister; it comes with the territory.
お姉ちゃんなので　しょうがないさ
Maria! We're staying here for the night.
マリア
今晩お兄ちゃんうちに泊まっていくからな
Come on, let's take a bath.
さっ　風呂入るぞ
お兄ちゃんと入り
I'll have mine with Big Brother...
- Idiot! I'm generously
gonna wash you, so be grateful!
- No! Lemme go, you poopy hag! Poopy!
馬鹿め　私がお前の体を洗ってやるから感謝しろ
いやいや　離せ　うんこくそ婆
- Oh, I'll get some sleep clothes for you.
- No! Lemme go, you poopy hag! Poopy!
あとで着替え用意しとくからな
Let me go, poopy hag!
離せ　くそ婆
Hey! Settle down!
ほら　大人しくしろ
Wait, where did Kobato go?
そういや　小鳩はどこ行ったか
Kobato?
小鳩
Big Brother, you perv!
お兄ちゃんのエッチ
I-I'm sorry!
ご　御免なさい
Care to justify yourself?
何か申し開きがあるかね　君
I'm sorry.
御免なさい
Okay, I forgive you.
よし　許す
Huh? Are you sure?
いいのかよ
You didn't actually peek on purpose, did you?
別にわざとのぞいたんじゃないだろう
O-Of course I didn't!
当たり前だろう　そんなの
So what good would it do to blame you?
だったらお兄ちゃんを責めても仕方ないさね
Plus, the fact that you don't give
excuses makes a good impression.
それにまあ　いいわけしないところも好印象だね
W-Well, because it's true
that I did something bad.
悪いことしたのは事実だから
You really are a good person.
I can see why Pegasus-san likes you.
お兄ちゃんは本当にいい人だね
天馬さんが気に入るのもわかるな
Are you friends with the President?
お前　理事長と仲いいのか
He and I are fishing buddies.
We especially like ayu fishing.
天馬さんとは釣り仲間なんさ
特に鮎釣りが好きでね
Huh, that's kind of surprising.
意外だな
You come along sometime!
今度　お兄ちゃんも一緒に行こうよ
Okay, got it.
わかった
それじゃ　お兄ちゃん　またね
Okay, see you later, Big Brother.
Yeah, see you at school.
また学校でな
Sheesh, I wish you really were our brother.
お兄ちゃんが本当のお兄ちゃんだったらよかったのにな
Or...
もしくは
Or something even more than that.
Personally, I think that might be nice.
もしくはそれ以外の関係になるのも
私としてはちょっといいかなって思うんだけど
But you've got Sena-san,
so I guess that's out...
まあ　星奈さんがいるからしょうがないかっと
O-Okay, later!
それじゃねえ
It wasn't long at all before
I learned what Kate's words meant.
俺がケイトの言葉の意味を知るのは　それからまもなくのことだった
A stray cloud blocks my view
光ったはずの星
迷った雲が邪魔して
Of the star I know should be shining there
見えなくなる
What should I believe in?
何を信じたらいい
I was on my way to breaking
不安定すぎる世界で
The treasure bred in this all too changeable world
育った宝物壊しかけてた
Because I was afraid of losing it
なくすのが怖くて
Those days of sighing "This is absurd"
不条理だって
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
And flailing inside my birdcage
We were gazing up at the same sky
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
When I gripped your hand,
you gripped back, didn't you?
君の手を握った時
握り返してくれたね
These joined hands are stronger than any wings
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
We can fly higher even without wings
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
So I know we'll be okay trying now
きっと今なら大丈夫
Let's grab the stars twinkling in the sky
大空輝く星を掴もう
Man, that was tasty!
Okay, let's go home and sleep.
食った　食った
帰って寝るか
Hey! Do the preview
like you're supposed to, hag!
こら　ちゃんと予告をやるのだ　婆
Oh, fine. Next time: "My Childhood
Friend Is Too Much of a Battleground."
しょうがないな
"My Childhood Friend Is
Too Much of a Battleground"
次回
「俺の幼なじみが修羅場すぎる」
Big Brother is really an adult
if he has a childhood friend!
幼なじみがいるなんてお兄ちゃんは大人だな
I want one too!
私も幼なじみ欲しいぞ
お前は現役で幼いだろうが
You're still in your childhood!
I bet in another five years,
Kobato-chan could be your childhood friend.
あと五年もすりゃ　小鳩ちゃんが幼なじみってことになるんじゃない
I don't want a poopy
vampire for a childhood friend!
うんこ吸血鬼が幼なじみなんていやなのだ
She'll stay my enemy forever!
あいつはこれからもずっと私の敵なのだ
Okay, okay.
はい　はい